<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Kumar Devvrat</title>
 <link href="http://kumardevvrat.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://kumardevvrat.github.io/"/>
 <updated>2014-04-02T21:00:46+05:30</updated>
 <id>http://kumardevvrat.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>Kumar Devvrat</name>
   <email>kumardevvrat@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Setting up Linux again</title>
   <link href="http://kumardevvrat.github.io/2014/04/02/setting-up-linux-again/"/>
   <updated>2014-04-02T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://kumardevvrat.github.io/2014/04/02/setting-up-linux-again</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;sdfdsfFor quite sometime, I was really busy with my desk job. I am mostly involved in Java related technologies and churning out code on IntelliJ IDEA/Windows here but I was getting annoyed with the ecosystem outside IntelliJ. Setting up any software on windows and specially specific toolchain is painful. I manage a lot of CentOS servers though but the joy of using and developing on linux is very good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I decided to use a VM. I have seen VirtualBox crashing at weird times but I did decide to use it nevertheless. Until now, I was using my linux config and package list from the college laptop. I decided that it was too stale now and maybe I need to jump into making out my own system again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I installed a vanilla Ubuntu 13.10 on the VM. There after it was easy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once setup, installed the following packages/software&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;awesome&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ZSH&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;terminator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;guake&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;exuberant-ctags&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;git&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vim-gnome&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Swap &lt;code&gt;Ctrl&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;Caps Lock&lt;/code&gt; because my hands are configured that way. Plus it is quite easy to use vim and other tools that way. Use &lt;code&gt;xmodmap&lt;/code&gt; to do that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setup oh-my-zsh and copy my old .zshrc files so that command line is all set&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setup quick shortcuts for guake (launch on &lt;em&gt;tilde&lt;/em&gt;) and others as well&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make awesome as the default desktop manager&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I decided to redo the vim config again. For the sane plugin management this time, I went with Vundle. It was very easy to set it up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I am past the days of setting up different desktop managers, installing new distros, compiling packages from source, getting those shiny gnome-shell customizations etc. Now I want a fast,  lightweight, no-nonsense working system. I have vim, zsh, guake, chrome and awesome. I feel good now.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A new start!</title>
   <link href="http://kumardevvrat.github.io/2014/04/02/A-new-start/"/>
   <updated>2014-04-02T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://kumardevvrat.github.io/2014/04/02/A-new-start</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am starting a new blog/site after a long time to put my things together or simply have an internet space of my own. I had purchased &lt;a href=&quot;http://devvrat.in&quot;&gt;devvrat.in&lt;/a&gt; back in 2010 and had written lot of stuff there. Unfortunately, it is all lost. I had hosted it on Wordpress at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.x10hosting.com&quot;&gt;x10Hosting&lt;/a&gt;. Wordpress had so many security exploits that I lost track of them. Every now and then, x10Hosting used to cancel my account and I used to plead them. At the end,  they terminated my account. I had backed up the wordpress install on my linux system from college but as it turns out that system is dead now. So well,  all the data is gone now!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am trying to assemble this one by simple static generator &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. It is tightly integrated with Github pages and I can simply write posts on &lt;code&gt;vim&lt;/code&gt; and do &lt;code&gt;git push&lt;/code&gt;. I find blogging with markdown syntax very slick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It so happens that I am starting on 2&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt; of April which is the start of the Hindu new year. For this year, apart from my desk job and startup ideas, I have clear cut learning goals. Let me see how that works out.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
